prisma an open source tool that makes it fun and safe to work with your database
prisma 一个开源工具，让使用数据库变得有趣和安全
the relational database is ancient technology that has stood the test of
关系数据库是经受住时间考验的古老技术，
time but writing sql code is not an ideal abstraction for modern app
但是编写 sql 代码并不是现代应用程序开发的理想抽象，
development it provides too much low level control and you'll probably blow
它提供了太多的低级控制和 你可能
your foot off writing it to address this concern orms like sqlize implement
会为了解决这个问题而
object relational mapping to express data with object oriented code like
javascript classes prisma is also an orm that addresses similar problems but
instead it has its own declarative schema definition language you write a
大发雷霆 你编写一个
schema to express your data and relationships in a human readable way or
模式来以人类可读的方式表达你的数据和关系，
the schema can be automatically inferred from any existing database prisma then
或者模式可以从任何现有的数据库棱镜中自动推断，然后
converts the schema into type definitions allowing you to perform
将模式转换为类型定义，允许你
typesafe crud operations with your own database models which means you get ide
使用自己的数据库模型执行类型安全的 crud 操作，这意味着你得到 ide
autocompletion tailored to your own custom schema in addition it handles
自动完成根据您自己的自定义模式量身定制，此外它还处理
migrations as your data structure evolves and if you want to visualize
migr 随着数据结构的发展，如果您想可视化
your data prisma studio allows you to view and manage all of your tables and
您的数据，prisma studio 允许您在浏览器中查看和管理所有表和
rows in the browser to get started you'll need a relational database like
行以开始使用，尽管支持 mongodb，但您需要一个关系数据库，如
mysql or postgres although mongodb is supported as well from a nodejs project
mysql 或 postgres从 nodejs 项目
run npx prisma init this creates a env file where you can add your database url
运行 npx prisma init 这将创建一个 env文件，您可以在其中添加数据库 url
and a prisma directory to define the schema if the existing database already
和 prisma 目录来定义架构如果现有数据库已经
has data we can run prismadb pool to introspect it and automatically generate
有数据，我们可以运行 prismadb pool 对其进行内省并自动
the schema from it notice how each table is represented with the model keyword
生成架构 它注意到每个表是如何用 model 关键字表示的，
then inside the braces we have column names and their data types as well as
然后在大括号内我们有列名和它们的数据类型以及
optional constraints like for example we might use relation to create a foreign
可选的约束，例如我们可以使用关系
key constraint between a weapon and a human and we can also index the weapon
在武器和人类之间创建外键约束，我们可以 还可以
id while we're at it the beauty of this is that the code is significantly more
在我们使用它的同时
concise than what you would write otherwise in raw sql now if we decide to
索引武器 ID  l 现在，如果我们决定
modify our schema like add an extra timestamp column we'll also need to
修改我们的模式，比如添加一个额外的时间戳列，我们还需要
modify the database structure which can be handled automatically with the prisma
修改数据库结构，现在可以使用 prisma
migrate command now to interact with the database on the server we tell prisma to
migrate 命令自动处理它，以便与服务器上的数据库交互，我们告诉 prisma
generate the client library import the client into a javascript file and notice
生成 客户端库将客户端导入 javascript 文件并注意
how it auto-completes the models in the schema if you do something wrong you'll
它如何自动完成模式中的模型如果你做错了你
know about it right away now find all the humans with the find menu method to
会马上知道的现在找到所有使用 find 菜单方法来
filter the results we can add a where clause as a plain javascript object and
过滤结果的人我们可以 添加 where子句作为纯 javascript 对象，
if we want to join a related table we can do that by adding the include object
如果我们想加入相关表，我们可以通过添加包含对象来做到这一点
prisma already knows how to run the complicated sql code under the hood and
prisma 已经知道如何在后台运行复杂的 sql 代码
returns the data as an array of javascript objects ready to use in your
并将数据作为javascript 对象数组返回 准备好在您的
application this has been prisma in 100 seconds if you want to see more short
应用程序中使用这已经在 100秒内成为 prisma 如果您想看到更多这样的短视频，请
videos like this hit the like button and subscribe and let me know if you want to
点击“赞”按钮并订阅，如果您想
see a full prisma tutorial in the comments thanks for watching and i will
查看完整的 pris，请告诉我 评论中的ma教程感谢观看，我会
see you in the next one
在下一篇中见到你